Finding Aid for Muschenheim, William. Architectural drawings and papers. 1925-1990
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Job 136, Museum of Art University of Michigan
    - Main Stair, Platforms and Exhibition Space 1957
      - Presentation Boards
        - Museum of Art, University of Michigan 1957 (Box B12)
  - Job 137, G. Bruce McCaleb
    - Alterations to Residence 1957
      - Papers
        - Original working drawings, pencil on tracing paper (Box B8)
  - Job 138, Ankers International Competition, Middle East Technical University:
    - Building for School of Administrative Sciences 1960
      - Drawings, 2 boards; 2 folders
        - Original Drawings and Sketches undated, pencil, colored pencil and colored marker on tracing paper (Map-case B3)
        - Mixed Prints, bluelines, blacklines and colored pencil on bluelines (Map-case B3)
        - Presentation Boards (2) (Map-case B3)
      - Papers (Box B8)
      - Photographs (Box B10)
  - Job 139, F.D.R. Memorial Competition
    - Memorial in Washington [Franklin Delano Roosevelt] 1961
      - Drawings, 2 boards; 2 folders
        - Original Sketches and Drawings undated (Map-case B3)
        - Mixed Prints undated (Map-case B3)
        - Presentation Boards, 2 boards (Map-case B3)
      - Papers (Box B8)
      - Photographs (Box B10)
  - Job 140, Joseph Blatt
    - Alterations to Residence [Consultation] 1960
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 141, Harry Lieberman
    - Designs for Development Houses 1960
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 143, A. Benjamin Handler
    - Alterations to Residence 1961
      - Papers
        - (includes original working drawing, pencil and yellow pencil on tracing paper) (Box B8)
  - Job 145, Robert E. Schwartz
    - Consultations-Church, Shopping Center 1963
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 146, Phi Epsilon Pi
    - Fraternity House Alterations and Annex 1966
      - Drawings, 9 folders
        - Topological Surveys 1962-1966, bluelines (Map-case B4)
        - Mixed Original Drawings 1962-1967, undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper; pencil on graph paper (Map-case B4)
        - Original Site Plan, Floor Plan, Section, Plot Plan undated, black ink on tracing paper (Map-case B4)
        - Original Working Drawings, A-F and 1-15 1962, 1966, pencil on tracing paper (Map-case B4)
        - Original Drawings: Details and Electrical, E Series-5B 1962, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper (Map-case B4)
        - Color Studies undated, colored pencil on bluelines (Map-case B4)
        - Furniture Layout Studies undated, pencil and blue marker on tracing paper; pencil and orange marker on bluelines; colored marker on tracing paper (Map-case B4)
        - Mixed Prints, including Electrical and Heating 1962-1965, orange marker on bluelines (Map-case B4)
        - Prints, "Set 33" 1965, bluelines (Map-case B4)
        - Prints, "Set 42" Office Copy, bluelines (Map-case B4)
      - Papers
        - Accounting, 2 folders (Box B8)
        - Catalogs (Box B8)
        - Certificates (Box B8)
        - Colors (Box B8)
        - Correspondence (Box B8)
        - Estimates (Box B8)
        - Kitchen (Box B8)
        - Legal (Box B8)
        - Miscellaneous (Box B8)
        - Notes and Memos (Box B8)
        - Orders (Box B8)
        - Original Drawings, Details, 1-8 through 30-8 (pencil on tracing paper) (Box B8)
        - Original Drawings, Studies (pencil on tracing paper) (Box B8)
        - Photographs and Plans of Original (Box B8)
        - Plans of Existing House (Box B8)
        - Prints, Details (bluelines and blacklines) (Box B8)
        - Proposal (Box B8)
        - Record of Issuance of Drawings and Specs (Box B8)
        - Reports (Box B8)
        - Samples (Box B8)
        - Specifications (Box B8)
        - Superintendence Reports (Box B8)
      - Photographs
        - Plischke (Box B11)
  - Job 147, Claude A. Eggersten
    - Addition to Residence 1966
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 149, Richard Stoll
    - Consultation re: Residence 1966
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 150, Alpha Ki Delta Sorority
    - Consultations re: Building 1957
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 152, Sleepy Hollow Cemetery
    - Gravestone, Lisa Muschenheim 1967
      - Papers (Box B8)
        (includes original sketches and drawings, pencil on tracing paper, and photographs)
  - Job 153, Emile Voelcker
    - Addition to Residence 1967
      - Papers (includes original drawings, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper) (Box B8)
  - Job 157, Mr. and Mrs. Ned Flanders
    - Alterations to Residence 1968
      - Drawings, 1 folders
        - Original Drawings 1968, marker and pencil on tracing paper (Box B5)
      - Papers (Box B8)
  - Job 160, Blue Cross, Blue Shield Detroit, 1 folders
    - Blue Cross, Blue Shield Detroit
      - Drawings
        - Prints, bluelines (Map-case B5)
  - Job 162, International Organization Headquarters and Conference Center, Vienna, Austria
    - International Competition 1969
      - Drawings, 3 folders
        - Original Drawings undated, cut paper and ink on vellum; pencil on tracing paper and vellum; black ink on vellum (Map-case B5)
          (includes "Exploding Tower Diagram")
        - Mixed Prints with Color, colored pencil, marker and ink on bluelines (Map-case B5)
        - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case B5)
      - Papers (Box B8)
      - Photographs (Box B10)
  - Job 163, Mr. and Mrs. Robert Knauss
    - Week-End House 1970
      - Drawings, 2 folders
        - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case B5)
        - Mixed Original Sketches and Drawings undated, colored marker on tracing paper and vellum; pencil on tracing paper and vellum (Map-case B5)
        - Mixed Prints, bluelines (Map-case B5)
      - Papers
        - Catalogs (Box B8)
        - Correspondence, Miscellaneous (Box B8)
        - Estimates, Contracts (Box B8)
        - Sketches (pencil and water color on graph paper) (Box B8)
        - Specifications (Box B8)
  - Job 169, Mr. Sabaliunas
    - Alteration to Residence [Consultation] 1969
      - Papers (Box B8)
        (includes original sketches, marker on graph paper)
  - Job 170, Mr. Lyne
    - Alterations to Residence
      - Drawings, 1 folders
        - Presentation Boards, 2 items (Map-case B5)
        - Mixed Original Drawings and Print 1969, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper; blueline (Map-case B5)
  - Job 172, Joseph T.A. Lee
    - Market Arbor "A" Center 1970
      - Drawings, 1 folders
        - Mixed Original Drawings, Prints and Presentation Board,1970 and undated, pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper and vellum; colored marker on blueline (Map-case B5)
      - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job 176, Rockresorts
    - Lobby-Board Room 1971
      - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job 177, Channing Jacque
    - Addition to Cottage 1971
      - Papers (Box B9)
        (includes original drawings, pencil on tracing paper; pencil and blue ink on tracing paper)
  - Job 178, A.B. Handler
    - Addition to House 1972
      - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job 181, City of Grand Rapids Museum
    - Re: Addition to Old Federal Building 1974
      - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job 183, Dr. Helen Gay
    - Addition to House 1976
      - Drawings, 1 folders
        - Original Drawings, pencil and red pencil on tracing paper and vellum (Map-case B5)
      - Papers
        - Accounting, Prints, Miscellaneous (Box B9)
        - Color Schedule (Box B9)
  - Job 184, Ara G. Paul
    - Addition and Alterations to House 1977, 1987
      - Drawings, 3 folders
        - Design Development, Studies undated, colored pencil and cut paper on tracing paper and Xerox prints (Map-case B5)
        - Original Working Drawings 1988, pencil and red pencil on vellum; pencil on tracing paper (Map-case B5)
        - Prints (Photocopy prints) (Map-case B5)
      - Papers
        - Accounting, Legal (Box B9)
        - Calculations, Surveys, Notes (Box B9)
        - Catalogs (Box B9)
        - Color Studies (paint and cut paper on Xerox prints) (Box B9)
        - Original Working Drawings, 1-15; 17 1977 (pencil on tracing paper and vellum) (Box B9)
        - Original Working Drawings, 19-21 (pencil on tracing paper and vellum) (Box B9)
      - Photographs (slides, color prints) (Box B11)
  - Job 186, Hermann Hermannsson
    - House 1980
      - Drawings, 2 folders
        - Original Sketches and Drawings 1980-1986, pencil and yellow pencil on vellum and tracing paper (Map-case B6)
        - Prints 1954-1984, bluelines (Map-case B6)
      - Papers
        - Accounting, Legal (Box B9)
        - Catalogs (Box B9)
        - Surveys (Box B9)
      - Photographs (Box B10)
  - Job 187, Silas Woods
    - House 1980, 1985
      - Drawings, 1 folders
        - Original Working Drawings 1981-1982, pencil on vellum (Map-case B6)
      - Papers
        - Accounting (Box B9)
        - Original Sketches (blue marker on tracing paper; colored pencil on tracing paper and yellow note paper) (Box B9)
  - Job 188, J.E. Keith Smith
    - Railing and Approach to Residence 1983
      - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job 189, Peter Meister
    - Alteration to Residence 1985
      - Papers (includes original working drawing, pencil and red ink on tracing paper)
        - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job190, Robert Cole
    - Consultation 1987
      - Papers (Box B9)
  - Job 191, Mr. and Mrs Dozauer
    - Residence Alterations 1987
      - Papers
        - Original Drawings, Color Studies (pencil and colored pencil on tracing paper; pencil on notebook paper) (Box B9)
        - Miscellaneous (Box B9)
  - Job 192, Astronaut's Memorial
    - Astronaut's Memorial
      - Drawings, 2 folders
        - Original Drawings and Sketches undated, pencil on tracing paper and vellum; black marker on tracing paper; colored pencil and black marker on vellum (Map-case B6)
        - Mixed Prints (Map-case B6)
  - Job 193, Otis Taylor
    - Consultation 1988
      - Papers
        - Catalogs, 2 folders (Box B9)
  - Unnumbered Projects
    - East Hampton Air Terminal
      - Drawings, 2 folders
        - Original Drawings undated, pencil on vellum; ink and pencil on mylar (Map-case B6)
        - Color Studies undated, colored pencil on Xerox prints; cut paper on Xerox prints (Map-case B6)
        - Presentation Boards (2) (Map-case B6)
    - Washington State Veteran's Memorial Competition undated, 1 folders
      - Drawings
        - Drawings, collage on blueline (Map-case B6)
    - Unidentified; Miscellaneous
      - Drawings (Map-case B6)
    - International Congress of Modern Architecture-Baltimore Map
      - Photographs (Box B10)
    - New School for Social Research
      (project done in collaboration with Joseph Urban)
      - Photographs (Box B10)
  - Miscellaneous files
    - Miscellaneous Folder of Unidentified Sketches and Calculations (Box B9)
    - Notes: Engineering Mechanics War Training Course, 1934-1936; volumes; 3 folders (Box B9)
    - Project Dividers in Box 14 (Dividers which were removed from Work Files. Those with significant written information were photocopied and are filed with relevant drawings) (Box B14)